Welcome back, In this video, we're going to do an extended example of SLR parsing.
欢迎回来，在这个视频中，我们将做一个单反解析的扩展示例。
To review, here is the parsing automaton for the grammar that we've been looking at
为了回顾一下，下面是我们一直在研究的语法的解析自动机
in the last couple of videos. And this is just the deterministic version of the, non
在最后几个视频里。这只是一个确定性的版本，非
deterministic automaton we built last time. And I've just gone through and
我们上次建造的确定性自动机。我刚看了一遍
numbered all of the states. So let's take a look at what happens when we parse the
给所有的州都编了号。那么让我们来看看当我们解析
input [inaudible] times [inaudible]. And just to review, we've appended dollar sign
输入[听不见]次[听不见]。再回顾一下，我们附加了美元符号
here to the end, to indicate where the end of the input occurs. That's just an end of
从这里到结尾，以指示输入结束的位置。这只是一个结束
input marker. And because this is the beginning of the parse we haven't seen any
输入标记。因为这是解析的开始，所以我们还没有看到
input yet. And so the vertical bar is all the way at the left hand side of the
还没有输入。所以竖线一直在左手边
input. So the machine begins in state one, and there's nothing on the stack. The
输入。所以机器从状态1开始，堆栈上没有任何东西。这个
vertical bar is all the way to the left again, so the stack is empty. So it just
竖线又一直靠左，所以堆栈是空的。所以它只是
terminates in state one. And these are the possible items, that are valid for the
以状态一终止。这些是可能的项，它们对
initial state of the parser. So among those items, we see that there are two
解析器的初始状态。所以在这些项目中，我们看到有两个
that tell us that it's okay to shift an integer in this state. And, of course, the
这告诉我们，在这种状态下移位整数是可以的。当然，还有
first input is an integer, and so there are no reduced moves. All the other items
第一个输入是整数，因此没有减少的动作。所有其他物品
in here also have their jobs all the way at the left side of the item, so there's
在这里也有他们的工作一直在物品的左边，所以有
no possible reduced move in this state. The only thing we could possibly do is
在这种状态下不可能减少移动。我们唯一能做的就是
shift, and it's okay to shift an integer. So to summarize, on the initial
移位，则可以对整数进行移位。所以总而言之，在最初的
configuration of the parser, the DFA halts in state one, it never even gets out of
配置解析器时，DFA会在状态1中暂停，它甚至永远不会离开
state one, so it starts there and ends there without even reading any input
状态1，所以它从那里开始，在那里结束，甚至没有读取任何输入
because the stack is empty and the action that, that state tells us to do is to
因为堆栈是空的，该状态告诉我们要做的操作是
shift. So that leads us in the following state, there's an int on the stack and we
换档。这将我们引向下面的状态，堆栈上有一个int，我们
have a times coming up on the input. So, what happens in that situation? Well, we
输入的时间快到了。那么，在这种情况下会发生什么呢？嗯，我们
begin. The automaton is going to read the stack. So, starting from the bottom of the
开始吧。自动机将读取堆栈。因此，从
stack, we're in the start state. And then we read an int, there's an int on the
史塔克，我们现在处于开始状态。然后我们读一个整型，上面有一个整型
stack, and we win d up in this state. And what does this state tell us we can do?
堆栈，我们在这种状态下赢得d。这个州告诉我们我们能做什么？
Well, it tells us one possibility is to reduce by T goes to int. But again, we
它告诉我们一种可能性是将T减去INT。不过，再说一遍，我们
will only do that, if the following input is in the follow of T, And times, which is
只有当下面的输入跟在T和时间之后时才会这样做，这是
the next input item, is not in the follow of T. So times is not in the follow. Of T
下一个输入项不在T后面，所以时间不在后面。的数量
and so reducing here is not a possibility. That leaves only the other item to
所以在这里减少是不可能的。这样就只剩下另一项要
consider and here we see that this item says we can the time. So if the times the
想想看，我们在这里看到，这一项说我们可以计时。所以如果泰晤士报
next thing in input, which it is, it's okay to shift. So the DFA halts in state
输入的下一件事，就是，可以换档了。所以DFA在状态下停止
three and because there's a times in the input the move is to shift. And that puts
三，因为在输入中有一个时间，所以移动是移位。这就把
us into this configuration where we have int and times on the stack. Times is at
我们进入这个配置，其中堆栈上有int和time。《泰晤士报》在
the top of the stack, int is below it and we have an int coming up in the input. So
堆栈的顶部，int在它的下面，我们在输入中出现一个int。所以
what happens now, again, the DFA is going to read the entire stack. So beginning at
现在会发生什么，同样，DFA将读取整个堆栈。所以从一开始就是
the bottom of the stack, the first thing it sees is an int, and it moves to that
在堆栈的底部，它首先看到的是一个int，然后移到那里
state. And then it sees a times, and so it moves to this state. And now, in this
州政府。然后它看到一个时间，所以它移动到这种状态。而现在，在这个
particular state, what are the possibilities? Well, we can see, first of
特定的州，有哪些可能性？那么我们可以看到，首先
all, that there are no reduced moves. There are no items with the dot all the
最重要的是，没有减少动作。所有的项目中都没有带圆点的项目
way at the right end. So the only possibility is a, is a shift. And we could
就在正确的一端。所以唯一的可能性就是一个，一个转变。我们可以
shift if the upcoming input's a open paren, which it's not. More usefully, we
如果即将到来的输入是开放的Paren(实际上不是)，则进行Shift。更有用的是，我们
could shift if the upcoming input is an [inaudible], which is exactly what we see.
如果即将到来的输入是[听不见的]，可能会发生变化，这正是我们所看到的。
So, the DFA terminates in state eleven, and the move in that state is to shift.
因此，DFA终止于状态11，并且在该状态下的移动是移位。
And that puts us into this state, where we have int times int on the stack, and we
这就把我们带到了这个状态，在这里我们在堆栈上有int次int，我们
are out of input. We are at the end of the input. So let's see what happens on the
都没有输入。我们已经在输入的末尾了。所以让我们来看看会发生什么
stack int times int. The automaton reads it int times int and it winds up back in
堆栈int乘以int。自动机读取它的int乘以int，它就会返回到
state three. Sa3 tells us that we can shift if the, next input item is a times
第三州。SA3告诉我们，如果下一个输入项是a次，我们可以进行移位
and which it is not. Or we can reduce, if whatever the next. Is in the next input is
但事实并非如此。或者我们可以减少，如果下一步有什么问题的话。在下一个输入中是
in the follow of T. And in fact dollar is in, the follow of T. So, in, the end of
在T后面，实际上美元是in，t后面是in，end，in，end of
the input come after a T on the stack. And that means it's fine to reduce by T goes
输入位于堆栈上的T之后。那就是说，用T来减少是可以的
to int. So, once we do that, once we do the reduction T goes to int, we wind up in
转到int。所以，一旦我们这样做了，一旦我们把T减去INT，我们最终得到
the state times T. That's our stack contents and of course we're still at the
状态时间T。这是我们的堆栈内容，当然我们还在
end of the input. So once again the DFA is going to read the entire stack contents
输入结束。因此，DFA将再次读取整个堆栈内容
from the bottom to the top. First it reads the int at the bottom of the stack, then
从下到上。它首先读取堆栈底部的int，然后
it sees the times. And then it finally reads the t at the top of the stack. And
它看得见时代。然后，它最终读取堆栈顶部的t。和
it winds up in a new state, state four. And the interesting thing about this
最后到了一个新的州，州四。有趣的是，这件事
particular step is that the DFA took a different path through the state graph
具体步骤是DFA在状态图中采用不同的路径
than it did the previous time. And that's because the stack contents changed. We
比上一次要好。这是因为堆栈内容改变了。我们
didn't just add stuff to the stack, and so we didn't extend the previous path. We
并不只是将内容添加到堆栈中，因此我们没有扩展前面的路径。我们
actually replaced some symbols or a symbol on the stack with a new symbol, in this
实际上用新符号替换了一些符号或堆栈上的符号，在此
case, the non-terminal T and that caused the DFA to take a different path. Now what
情况下，非终端T，这导致DFA采用不同的路径。现在怎么办？
does this item in state four tell us to do? Well it says that we can reduce by T
第四州的这个项目告诉我们要做什么吗？上面说我们可以减少T
goes to N times T if whatever. Follows in the input is in the follow of T. And, once
如果有的话，就是N乘以T。后面的输入跟在T的后面，并且，ONCE
again, dollar is in the follow of T. And so we'll do that reduction, and now we're
再说一次，美元紧随T之后，所以我们要减去，现在我们
left with the static contents just consisting of T. And, of course we're
剩下的静电内容只包含T，当然，我们是
still at the end of the input. And let's see what happens now. So now of course the
仍然在输入的末尾。让我们看看现在会发生什么。所以现在当然
contents of the stack have changed even more radically and so the DFA just goes
堆栈的内容发生了更大的变化，所以DFA就这么走了
off in a completely different direction. It reads T winds up in this state and this
朝完全不同的方向走去。上面写着T在这个州结束，然后这个
state says we can either shift a plus if there's a plus in the input. And again,
州政府说，如果输入中有加号，我们可以移动一个加号。再一次，
there's no more input. Or we can reduce by E goes to T if dollar, if the end of the
没有更多的输入了。或者我们可以减去E，如果美元变成T，如果
input is in the follow of E, Which it is. And so the reduction will be the one that
输入是跟在E后面的，它是这样的。所以减少的数量将会是
we do. And now we have, this stack contents, consisting only of E. Let's see
我们有。现在我们有了这个堆栈内容，只由E组成，让我们看看
what happens in that situation. Now we make a transition to this state, state
在那种情况下会发生什么。现在我们过渡到这个状态，状态
two. And we only have one item, S prime goes to E dot. And so this is a reduced
二。我们只有一项，S一等数是E点。所以这是一个简化的
move. And again, dollar is in the follow of S prime, ' cause that is the start
移动。再一次，美元紧跟在S质数之后，因为这是开始
symbol. And since that is the start symbol, we accept at this point. So once
符号。因为这是开始符号，我们在这一点上接受。所以有一次
we get to that item as our, reduce move, we know that the input has been
我们到达该项目作为我们的Reduce移动，我们知道输入已经
successfully parsed.
已成功解析。